Hero. Icon. Dissenter.
RBG is a documentary film directed by Betsy West.
Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg now 84, and still inspired by the lawyers who defended free speech during the Red Scare, Ginsburg
refuses to relinquish her passionate duty, steadily fighting for equal rights for all citizens under the law.
Through intimate interviews and unprecedented access to Ginsburg’s life outside the court, RBG tells the electric story of Ginsburg’s consuming love affairs with
both the Constitution and her beloved husband Marty—and of a life’s work that led her to become an icon of justice in the highest court in the land.
Self, played by Ruth Bader Ginsburg.
Self, played by Jane C. Ginsburg.
Self, played by James Steven Ginsburg.
Self, played by Nina Totenberg.
Self, played by Clara Spera.
Self, played by Gloria Steinem.
RBG is a 2018 American documentary film focusing on the life and career of Ruth Bader Ginsburg, the second
female Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States after Sandra Day O'Connor.
After premiering at the 2018 Sundance Film Festival, the film
was released in the United States on May 4, 2018.
The film was directed and produced by Betsy West and Julie Cohen.
The film received positive reviews from critics and
grossed $14.4 million worldwide.
It was chosen by the National Board of Review as the Best Documentary Film of 2018, and
nominated for several other awards, including the BAFTA Award for Best Documentary.
At the 91st Academy Awards, the film earned nominations for Best
Documentary Feature and Best Original Song ("I'll Fight").
The film also won the Cinema for Peace Award for Women's Empowerment in 2019.
The film explores themes of biography, supreme court,
woman director, supreme court justice.